Let's look at Gen-X versus Linux and see what are the differences.
But before we get into finding the differences we'll find out what Unix is.
Unix was first developed for multi-user and multitask purposes in mid 1970s in Bell Labs by AT&T G and
Massachusetts Institute of Technology.
There was an operating system but it was not allowing for multi users or multitasking.
So that was one of the purposes for creating the then born Linux in 1991.
But Abdoun named linux towards Linux is mostly free and Linux is open source.
So what Linux Free means is you could install the Linux operating system in any of your computer hardware.
There are a few Linux distributions that are not free like redhat where you would have to pay for support
and subscription and open source means that Linux code that was derived from Unix is actually open to
the public to the community so they can go in and make changes to their code and make the operating
system the way they want it to work in their way.
Unix is mostly used by sun and the operating system is called Solaris.
By the way sun is now bought out by Oracle and also other operating systems that are Unix as used as
HP ex-spy HP A-I X and some other distributions of Unix Linux is used mostly by developer communities
or companies like redhat cental West Debian Fedora are Susie buntu and there are so many of them.
Even if you go out and search for Linux distributions you will find so many of them.
Unix is comparatively support and very few are a file system.
Now what is a file system.
That is something that we will Khowar later.
But there are fewer file system that supported by Unix operating system and a lot more file systems
that are supported in Linux flavors.
Linux can be installed on a variety of computer hardware ranging from mobile homes tablet video games
console to mainframe and super super computers is just like you cannot install Mac operating system
on a Dell machine.
You have to install Mac operating system on a Mac hardware just like that.
Unix is only installed on certain hardware as Linux you could install pretty much on every hardware
that is out there running MDO Intel processor.
So these are the few basics about Unix and and Linux and I hope you will find more information if you
you're curious about it online.